Hari Ram

hram3348@gmail.com | 8248052413 | www.linkedin.com/in/hariram-r

Summary

Android professional with over 4 years of experience specialized in designing, developing, testing and maintaining android applications. Proven ability to build android applications from scratch and to scale them up as per the business needs.

Skills

Languages: Java, Dart, Kotlin, SQL

Technologies: Flutter, MVVM, ROOM, Git, Firebase Firestore, Crashlytics, Jetpack Components, RxJava

Professional Experience

Ivy Mobility Solutions Pvt Ltd

Software Engineer Android

Jun 2021 - Present

- Team Management Managed Team with 8 android developers to develop the application
- Developing an application that allows to place orders of goods by the retailers
- Created application using Java, Kotlin and SQLite
- Written efficient and reusable code and maintained clean code with MVVM architecture

Innovasphere Infotech

Android Developer

Jun 2018 – Jun 2021

- Built over 6 applications from scratch which are all available in play store
- GPS tracking and Mobile payment features have brought 5+ new schools to the application
- Developed applications which are all having over 10k downloads
- Fixed bugs in short time through which maintained above 4 star rating in play store
- Used MVVM architecture pattern, Java and Flutter
- Integrated flavors, payment gateways, in app update, firebase push notifications, file sharing

Certificate

IICT Chrompet
Android Development Course

Aug 2017 - Jan 2018

Education

Jerusalem College Of Engineering B.Tech Information Technology

Sept 2014 - Apr 2018

Projects

IvyCPG

Description: An android app that allows retailers to place orders of goods. Fixed a major ANR using RxJava. Built a strong local database and backend setup.

Technologies: Java, Kotlin, SQLite, RxJava, Crashlytics, Retrofit, Android studio

Eplus MLZ

Description: Eplus MLZ enables school students to monitor the activities related to their school. Developed the app from scratch to upload it into the play store which has over 15k downloads.

Technologies: Java, Crashlytics, Retrofit, GPS tracking, ZOOM, Payment gateway, Android studio

EPFuture Teachers

Description: EPFuture Teachers helps school teachers to follow up their day to day activities at school. File sharing, Location based attendance and Video conferencing are some of the highlights of the app.

Technologies: Java, Crashlytics, Retrofit, ZOOM, Android studio

ELearning

Description: This application helps school students to prepare for their exams. Fixed bugs efficiently to keep the rating of the application above 4 stars in the play store which is having 10k+ downloads.

Technologies: Java, Crashlytics, Retrofit, Shared preferences, Android studio

Second Innings

Description: An android app to schedule, participate and view the stats of tournaments.

Technologies: Java, Crashlytics, Retrofit, Shared preferences, Payment gateway, Android studio

EPFuture Management

Description: A Flutter app which is used by the promoters and principals of schools. Built the UI in dart to digitize managing activities of school.

Technologies: Flutter, Dart, Crashlytics, Dio, Shared preferences, Android studio